Al!
Sensei!
Brother!
That right arm of yours
is a nuisance.
I'm going to pull off
all that useless stuff—
those ugly mechanical parts!
What did you call them?!
And then I'm going to take
everything that is left over.
Why, you!
Why, you...
Al!
Al, no!
Al...
Brother,
you said that homunculi
can't use alchemy, right?
But this guy is different.
I've figured out what his secret is.
When his right arm and left leg form a circle,
he can transmute the outside of his body into other materials.
He can change his body
because he's a homunculus.
But he can use alchemy because...
Because he has Ed's limbs
in those places?
My...?
Give them back!
Those belong to Brother!
They are Brother's arm and leg!
Give them back!
Why, you!
Al!
Fine by me!
Brother!
Al! Please, stop already!
What are you talking about?
He's a homunculus.
He's not human.
But still, that boy is Izumi-san's—
Maybe so...
You want my arm, do you?
It's my arm!
You gained something for the price of this leg, didn't you?
You paid for your brother
with this arm.
In that case, what are you going to pay to deprive me of my arm and leg?
An equivalent exchange.
Stop jerking me around!
Ed!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Sensei...
Ed! Al!
I forbid you to get involved!
That boy is my sin,
and I will...
Sensei!
Hold it!
Winry! Take care of Sensei!
Just a minute! Ed! Al!
Fullmetal Alchemist, I understand this is the island where you did your training.
Brother, that woman...
Führer, what are you doing here?
It appears we are looking for the same thing as you are.
A homunculus?
I hear that's what
the enemy calls itself.
However,
do you guys know how a homunculus is born?
According to tradition, it's said that
a homunculus is the grown-up form
of the botched product that is born when someone attempts a human transmutation.
It was written in your
father's research as well.
I couldn't care less
about the guy.
That's fine.
But if the boy whom Lt. Col.
Archer found really is a homunculus,
that would mean that someone had attempted a human transmutation.
Human transmutation is impermissible, no matter what the circumstances are.
Do you have any idea
who this person might be?
Never mind that, we should be after the escaped homunculus.
Our men are already pursuing him.
I'm sorry, but I don't know.
We're in a hurry here, so if you don't mind...
Brother...
We can't tell them
about Sensei, you know.
Maybe so, but...
Well? How does it feel, holding him?
It's not bad.
Wrath... That makes all seven of us.
After all this time, how about we go to that woman's place?
Luckily, it's close by, and we do need to tell her about Greed.
Why Greed?
Because long ago,
she's the one who created Greed.
Why?!
Why did you show that
to my brother?!
The man understood
everything I told him.
What I handed down to him were the ancient memories of the Ishbalan people.
And as a result, my brother...!
You must not forget.
Inside here, they are still alive.
Countless lives...
He's here!
Here he is!
Due to circumstances beyond our control, we left our established residences.
As their leader, I will bear full responsibility.
You do know that new residences have been established here in the south, right?
You will all be taken there.
Make sure that you tell them not to offer any resistance.
Right.
However, before that happens, we will be checking everyone's names and faces.
Every last one of you.
Is there someone
you're looking for?
Begin.
Please, be careful.
I'm sure I saw
that homicidal maniac from Central.
I saw his wanted poster at the home of someone I was taking care of earlier.
Let's hope you didn't
mistake him for someone else.
Mama!
All right, you all!
Hey, where is he?!
The man with the X-shaped scar!
It won't do you
any good to hide him!
What's going on here?!
J-Just you try doing anything against me!
The military won't stand for—
A-A gunshot?!
I didn't hear any gunfire!
Stop! Don't shoot!
Stop firing, you stupid bastards!
Everyone, calm down!
Who was it that
acted against this man?
Is the massacre
going to repeat itself?!
We've already had
too much of this!
Right! How can we
keep silent any longer?!
I'm sick of being under the military's thumb!
Our people have been killed!
Go back to where
you came from, now!
Yeah! Get out of here!
Yow!
I'm going to suppress them.
Cover me.
Colonel?
What are you waiting for? I told you to cover me!
And wipe your forehead, would you?
Yes, sir!
Good grief.
What a pathetic story, both for master and pupil.
Ed, Al...
Still, I must draw the line somewhere.
You are expelled.
I did not teach you alchemy so that your bodies would end up like this.
I don't want to see any more of
your disgraceful fighting, either.
Sensei...
Thank you... for taking care of us.
Please, take care.
Are you two sure you just
want to go back home like this?
Okay, then...
Yeah.
Come by again
if you're ever around.
But...
She expelled us, and all, right?
Foolish bastards!
Now that you are
neither master nor pupil,
it means you can start dealing with each other as equal individuals.
That's right!
Now, you don't have to feel so constrained by her, do you?
Dammit. Al, we're going back!
Huh? Mm-hmm!
Don't go getting killed.
Sensei!
We came here to get some kind of lead as to how to get our original bodies back!
We're not leaving empty-handed!
Leave!
We're not leaving.
We want to know the whereabouts of a true Philosopher's Stone,
not the one made by
sacrificing human lives.
Leave.
We're not leaving!
I'll cut you up!
Cut us if you will...
...but we're not leaving!
I'm sure that returning that boy over to the other side is...
That is my sin.
I cannot teach you how to do it.
We will take the sin upon ourselves as well!
You morons...
You have someone
watching the brothers, right?
Yes, sir.
Don't be caught off guard.
If anything happens, let me know immediately.
Yes, sir.
The Elric brothers again?
What choice do we have?
We received a response from Central that
the Führer did in fact drop by down south here
and conducted his own personal investigation into the homunculus.
Which is exactly the opposite of what they said yesterday.
And with investigations
pertaining to the homunculi
now under the direct
supervision of the Führer?
We find out everything the brothers know, like we were originally going to.
There's the possibility that
the Chimera might appear again.
Kimbly too.
Let's go.
This is a foul place
we've come to.
Greed-san?
Roa, you guys
go back to Devil's Nest.
Are you going off
someplace by yourself?
There's just something
that's been bothering me.
I see.
So, Al, you don't remember anything about the other side of the doorway, huh?
No.
If not, then Al's body,
together with those memories,
could still be on the other side.
How can we get them
back from there?
If we use a Philosopher's Stone, then we can ignore the Principle of Equivalent Exchange
and open the doorway once again.
Equivalent exchange, huh?
Ed, do you believe in that?
Of course he does!
In order for something to be obtained, it must be accompanied by something of equal value.
And not just in alchemy, that's a principle throughout the whole world.
If that's so,
then that boy lost his own life before he was ever born.
And what did he obtain
for that price?
Apparently, I'm not that good a teacher.
Mason!
Yes?
Show these two where Dante-san's house is.
Tomorrow, I'll have them
go there to get some medicine.
Did you think you were
going to stay here for free?
I wonder what kind of person this Dante-san is.
A famous pharmacist,
from what Mason-san said.
Brother, there's something that's been bothering me.
Supposing that homunculi are born when a human transmutation fails...
Come on, Al,
let's get a move on!
Anyone home?
We've been expecting you.
Dante-sama is waiting for you inside.
Huh?
It's you!
Lyra-san?
Lyra?
I'm terribly sorry for what happened on that occasion.
What are you doing here?
I am employed here
as Dante-sama's pupil,
so that I may become as superb an alchemist as she is.
Dante-san is an alchemist?
Yes.
This is all thanks to you.
You taught me something important.
Your character has
completely changed, huh?
Come in.
I have brought them.
I've been waiting for you,
Elric brothers.
You're Dante-san?
Yes.
I was surprised to find that you were Izumi's students.
I've heard what is going on.
I will get her medicine ready at once.
U-Um, by any chance, did our teacher also...?
Yes. Long ago,
she learned alchemy here.
Really?
Yes.
Then, Dante-san, that makes you
our teacher's teacher!
I suppose that's what it means.
Hey, now, how did a guy
like me get to be so lucky?
And here I just came by to see a familiar face.
Well,
there's no letting them out of my sight now.
Are you serious about that?
You are a fellow State Alchemist.
Hey, we just got word from Greed-san.
It sounds like he needs some more hands.
Please, think it over.
Dante-san, why did you decide to become an alchemist?
Let's see...
It may sound corny,
but I suppose it was because I wanted to help people.
Alchemy is something
that people need.
Of course, the alchemy by itself isn't anything all that special.
But still, when it comes to working to help others,
that's something
that alchemy can do.
I'd like for people that strive to be happy to be rewarded for as hard as they work.
That's the way I felt.
Equivalent exchange?
Yes.
People can only gain one thing for one effort.
That is the absolute truth.
Dante-san, what do you think
about the Philosopher's Stone?
Are you two searching for
the Philosopher's Stone too?
N-No, we were...
All those who have sought the Philosopher's Stone
have been driven to despair.
It may be that it is too soon for mankind to acquire the Stone.
You know, you bear
such a resemblance to him.
Your father, Hohenheim the Light,
also sought the Philosopher's Stone.
Our father did?
Do you know
where your father is?
I don't even want to know.
Brother...
They've split up.
Handle the rest
like we planned.
Got it?
Go!
Now then...
You...!
Why, you!
You must be surprised.
I call it the Mightiest Shield.
Lyra-san?
Lyra-san!
Don't move!
As long as you don't resist,
I have no intention of harming her.
Dante-san!
Good day.
Who are you folks?
We're kidnappers.
Kidnappers?
Alphonse Elric,
I'm sorry, but you'll
have to come with us.
But Sensei taught me that
I shouldn't go with strangers.
What are you, stupid? Just how old are you?
Fourteen.
If you're fourteen,
then you're old enough to think and behave all by yourself, aren't you?
Listen up.
If you're a real man, you'll act on your own will!
Mm-hmm.
You can't go on forever doing things just because your teacher said to.
I get it. I have to think for myself, huh?
Exactly.
Now that you've figured that out, come with us—
After thinking about it for myself,
I've decided that I'm not
going to go with strangers.
Not bad.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 33: "Al, Captured"
I have no intention of negotiating with the thugs who have taken my brother!